# **Eros Casas**

Chicago, IL 60608 ◆ (312) 219-0113 ◆ ecasas182015@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Computer Programmer able to adapt to new concepts when developing applications, forms, and databases. Able to learn new languages and refine methods already learned in the past. Able to work with others in projects and explain concepts not understood well by others. In addition, Three years of technology support helps build patience and communication with customers and coworkers.

### SKILLS

- Hardware and software monitoring
- Github efficient
- Problem Solving
- Information gathering and analysis
- SQL knowledgeable

- Windows, Mac, and Linux efficient
- Microsoft Office proficiency
- Communication
- Java, JavaScript, and Python efficient
- Angular and React.js efficient

## WORK HISTORY

#### Hardware Software Technician, 10/2016 to 12/2019

Luther College – Decorah, Iowa

- Solving software and hardware problems involving both faculty and students
- Replaced hardware components within complex computer builds and identified any damage the computer was at risk of
- Ensured to carefully follow procedures to extracted user's data from hardware and to prevent data corruption
- Explained technological terms in a way non-tech users will easily understand
- Deployed software to Luther College workstation remotely and in-person
- Created and added in documentation to the Help desk and Hardware procedures

#### **Internship Student**, January 2018

Whole Foods – Chicago, IL

- Analyze the work environment and expectation for delivering code.
- Explored new languages such as Angular and React.
- Learned to be flexible and have a will to learn new technologies.

#### **Support Technician**, 05/2017 to 08/2017

Luther College – Decorah, IL

- Spend time on assisting and receiving feedback in improving the Luther College software.
- Gave feedback on ways to improve the Luther's Ticketing system.
- Worked in other departments outside the Technology Help Desk when workers were needed such as the software department.
- Spent time re imaging Luther College computer for the upcoming semester.
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for Luther employees.
- Troubleshoot and diagnose problems to accurately resolve a wide range of technical issues.

#### **Assistant**, 06/2014 to 08/2014

### **Chicago Public Schools**

• Research public school information in the database.

• Assisted in organizing events, filing important papers, and proper destruction of confidential papers.

## EDUCATION

**Bachelor of Arts**: Computer Science, 06/2020

Luther College - Decorah, IA

## **C**ERTIFICATIONS

## **Learning Docker**

LinkedIn

Issued July 2020 - No Expiration Date

## **Learning React.js**

LinkedIn

Issued Jan 2020 - No Expiration Date

## **Microsoft Office Specialist**

• Excel 2010, Powerpoint 2010, Word 2010